MONICA SILABAN

+6289520203763 | silabanmonica8@gmail.com | Medan, Indonesia

https://www.linkedin.com/in/monica-silaban/ | monica062 (monica062) · GitHub

PROFILE

I am a final year student majoring in information technology who is interested in software development and quality testing. Have experience in project work and active in organization, creative thinker, conscientious and loves to analyze. Have good communication skills and can work individually or in groups.

EDUCATION

Institut Teknologi Del - Laguboti

Aug 2022 - Present

Diploma in Information Technology, 3.46/4.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

SHORT FILM MAKING AND SOCIALIZATION: ADAPTION OF LOCAL CONTENT STORYBOOK "SEMANGAT ULI MERAIH MIMPI" – Student Creativity Program (PKM)

Apr 2024 - Present

- Drafting a film script that reflects the essence of the adapted storybook.
- Portraying the Main Character in the film, playing the role of Uli.
- Participating in the film editing process to ensure the desired consistency of the storyline and visual quality

QUALITY ASSURANCE MANUAL INTERNSHIP – PT CITRA PACIFIC MANDIRI

Jan 2024 - Mar 2024

- Do a manual testing to the software to ensure the function runs properly
- Create a testing documentation, include the bug testing and the reports
- Find the root problems that cause the software bugs
- Participate effectively with developers and project manager

SKILLS

TOOLS

• Programming Language: HTML, CSS, C, Java, Javascript, PHP, Phyton

• Database System : MySQL, SQL Yog, SQL Server

Framework
 Bootstrap, Laravel, Selenium (Robot Framework, Cucumber)
 Technology
 Github, Postman, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse IDE, PyCharm
 Miscellaneous
 Bizagi, Visual Paradigm, Star UML, Power Designer, Draw.io

LANGUAGE

• Indonesia (Fluent), English (Conversational Proficiency)

PROJECTS

TICKET BOOKING WEBSITE DESIGN OF KOPERASI BINTANG TAPANULI (KBT)

Jan 2024 - Jun 2024

Project Manager, Quality Assurance

 This final project developed an online ticket booking website for Koperasi Bintang Tapanuli (KBT) using the Laravel framework and PHP, with thorough testing and validation conducted using Cucumber and Robot Framework.

ADMIN APPS FUNCTIONAL TESTING - PT CITRA PACIFIC MANDIRI Jan 2024 - Mar 2024

Quality Assurance Manual

• This project involved conducting manual testing to ensure the proper functioning of the software, creating testing documentation, including bug reports, identifying root causes of software bugs, and using Google Sheets for manual documentation.

DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE SITANI WEBSITE

Jan 2023 - Jun 2023

System Analysis, UX Research

• This final project developed a website using the Laravel framework and PHP to help farmers easily borrow agricultural equipment without having to find the equipment owner.

BOOK DEVELOPMENT OF DISCRETE MATHEMATICS PROBLEM Des 2022 SOLVING WITH COMPUTATIONAL THINKING

Author

This project creates a book that discusses discrete math concepts with a computational thinking approach
to problem solving.

ORGANIZATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

ORGANIZATION

- Secretary of the Election Commission (KPU) for the Election of May 2024 Present BEM Chairperson and Vice Chairperson
- Member of BEM, Department of On-Campus Center

Sept 2023 - Present

CERTIFICATIONS

- Junior Developer from the National Professional Certification Agency (BNSP)
- Participant in Junior Web Developer Training under the Digital Talent Scholarship 2024
- Participant in Data Analyst and AI MariBelajar Scholarship Programs 2024